Contact

510-677-1508 (Mobile) jgreene510@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/jgreene510 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Windows Server Servers

Troubleshooting

Languages

English

Certifications

CompTIA A+

John Greene

Owner/Operator of Greene PC Repair at Greene PC Repair San Leandro

Summary

15+ years working in IT.Able to work within a group or unsupervised.Usually a team leader.

Specialties: Windows XP, Vista, Server 2003, Sever 2008 R2 proficient, Windows 7, Windows 8, Windows 10 and Mac OS X Experience as well as Microsoft Exchange and Remote Desktop expertise. I am also very well versed in help desk support and trouble ticket prioritization and escalation.

Experienced with many different versions of Linux (primarily Debian based distributions).

PC Hardware expert/ upgrade advisor/ custom PC builder: I specialize in building new systems with current generation technology as well as keeping older systems running like new when they slow down. I do this by assessing the users needs and seeing what upgrades to hardware (or software) could be beneficial to their uses. It could be replacing a dual core CPU with a quad core CPU, adding additional memory to the computer or replacing a traditional rotating drive with a solid state device. It could also be something like adding a graphics card to a system (especially useful in multimonitor situations) or adding additional storage (adding hard drives or replacing failing/failed drives.)

Also trained to repair View Interactive Entertainment Core computers an eCast MoJO core computers

Experience

Greene PC Repair
Owner/Operator of Greene PC Repair
January 2001 - Present (20 years 8 months)

San Leandro, CA

New: After a long hiatus I've decided to return to my Freelancing roots and offer my services. It seems now more than ever people need to have reliable computers and connectivity in a world of Zoom meetings, Remote Working, and Social Distancing.

My job is to build custom computers per the customer's request as well as assist with any tech support needs. I can build anything from a simple office computer with everything built onto the motherboard with a small amount of memory and a small hard drive all the way up to high end, multi-video card gaming computer. I also perform some home networking via Wi-Fi and cable routing (Cat 5e/6/6a) as well as helping end users set up DSL /Cable Internet access.

A large part of this job is providing desk-side support to the end users, or remote support if they prefer (using tools such as TeamViewer). I can troubleshoot issues such as slow PC performance, virus removal, helping install software (if the client had trouble with a install, which is rare) and also install hardware such as printers and scanners. If asked to I would also perform hardware upgrades, and advise any "future-proofing" of systems that weren't quite old enough to necessitate retirement, but were not performing as expected.

Green Packing, Inc.
Office Manager
February 2018 - February 2019 (1 year 1 month)
Union City, CA

At Green Packing, Inc. I handles all the paperwork for deliveries both in and out of our warehouse as well as the general office stuff like answering calls, customer service, and e-mailing customers to give them status updates. Also a large part of the job is data entry and some light IT work (fixing whatever breaks, troubleshooting internet connection and shared drives, setting up new computers and office equipment).

Lumens Integration, Inc.
Technical Support
August 2012 - March 2013 (8 months)
Fremont, CA

During my time at Lumens Integration my primary role was as technical support for the customers that would call in and have trouble with the product. Primarily educators with little to no IT training. It was my job to assist them

in setting up digital document cameras via telephone or written instructions (via e-mail) and, if needed, to authorize a return to our facility for a factory reconditioned device. Our ticketing system/CRM was NetSuite.

Also part of my job was to repair any and all computer problems that arose in the office. Mostly we used iMac's and Macbook Pro's, and when we had a hardware issue and we needed a hard drive swapped, memory changed out, or a screen replaced I was the go to guy. Lastly, I was also responsible to expanding our wireless network to our conference room and imaging any newer PC for deployment

For Me To Coupon Client Services Representative March 2011 - February 2012 (1 year)

San Leandro, CA

My role at FMTC was as the weekend Client Services Representative. I was working out of my home because this was a small start up and they were located in Texas. Most of my job was tending a queue and updating it regularly to see if any prospective customers were looking for a trial of the services offered by the company (Affiliate Marketing).

I would answer any questions about the company that would be e-mailed in by customers and handle any and all problems that arose with existing customers. Things like their data feed wouldn't download or change names on billing information. Anything account related. If it was something over my head I would escalate to my manager. Our CRM/Ticketing system was SalesForce.com.

It was also part of my job to investigate new leads and source them through message boards, updating the company blog, and through Google keyword searches.

Synarc, Inc.

IT Technician Level III

December 2007 - October 2008 (11 months)

My job duties included installation (both hardware and software), repair and preventative maintenance on our computers and related systems. I also assisted in determining suitable software and hardware to meet user requirements. Another duty of mine was to troubleshoot software and hardware (both desk side and via remote desktop and/or by phone or e-

mail communication) failures as well as identify network problems when they involved employee's computers. I also assisted in network maintenance.

I was also charged with a few special projects during my time at Synarc. One of the major projects was inventory control and roll out of new systems. We were retiring older Dell hardware (mostly Latitude D series laptops and Optiplex series workstations) and replacing them with newer and more robust systems from IBM/Lenvo (I was in charge of imaging and deployment) namely IBM/Lenvo Think Station's as well as Think Centre's and ThinkPad's.

I was also the first point of contact for new employee account creation in Active Directory and setting up user permissions and grouping as well as performing e-mail administration in a Microsoft Exchange 2003/2007 environment. Our ticketing system was Altiris. We used the same system for asset management and image deployment/creation.

View Interactive Entertainment Customer Service/ Help Desk March 2007 - October 2007 (8 months) San Leandro, California, United States

My job duties at View were as follows: Repair custom computer cores, touch screen monitors, Uninterruptible power supplies, etc. Provide Tier 1 and 2 support to customers who are having questions or problems. Track and log all customer interaction as well as outgoing and inbound repairs. Perform administrative tasks including account and contact information gathering, order entry, trouble ticket creation, etc, and entering information into a

Futurequest Systems
Custom Computer Assembler/Engineer
January 2006 - February 2007 (1 year 2 months)

Fremont, California, United States

SalesForce.com based CRM system.

My job was to build custom computers per the customer's request. I would build anything from a simple office computer with everything built onto the motherboard with a small amount of memory and a small hard drive all the way up to a 4U rack-mount server. Most builds were for local businesses and at the time were using a combination of Pentium IV processors and AMD Athlon64 processors. I was also part of quality assurance and was responsible for inspecting products for damage or flaws before shipment.

Lastly I was one of three people who were charged with rack-mount chassis modification for clients.

Education

Alameda County Office of Education Certificate (CompTIA A+) · (2000 - 2000)

Chabot College Computer Sciences · (2002 - 2004)

Arroyo High School

General Education, Computer Installation and Repair/ PC Networking and Security · (1995 - 2000)